Good evening ladies and gentlemen. A
very warm welcome to ICICI Lombard
Gender Insurance Company Limited Q3 and
9 months FY 2026 earnings conference
call from the senior management. We have
with us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and
CEO of the company. Mr. Gopal
Balachandran CFO Mr. Anand Singhi, Chief
Retail and Government. Mr. Girish Nayak,
Chief Technology and Health Underwriting
and Claims. Mr. Sep Gada, Chief
Corporate Solutions International and
Bank assurance. And Mr. Goro Vora, Chief
Reinsurance, Underwriting and Claims for
Property and Casualty.
Please note that any statements,
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on the information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involved risks and
uncertaintities which could cause
results to differ materially from the
current views being expressed. As a
reminder, all participant lines will be
in the listenonly mode and there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO ICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you sir.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call for ICL Lombard for quarter 3 and 9
months financial year 2026.
At the outset, let me wish you all a
very happy new year and best of health
and happiness.
I would like to give you a brief
overview of the recent economic and
industry trends which has shaped the
operating environment over the past few
months. Following that, our CFO Mr.
Gopal Balach Chandran will take you
through the company's financial
performance for the recently concluded
quarter and 9 months. The Indian economy
recorded a GDP growth of 8.2% in quarter
2 up from 7.8 in the preceding quarter.
The expansion was underpinned by
substained government capital
expenditure coupled with an increase in
private capex rupees service activi
services activity and a rebound in
private consumption. Consumption was
further supported by easing inflation
and the GST rationalization implemented
in late September 2025.
Coming to Q3 financial year 2026, the
index of industrial production, IIP data
indicates positivity supported by
manufacturing growth, continued
infrastructure development and a
turnaround in consumer goods segment. EV
bill generation and toll collections
during the same period recorded growth
of 13% and 17% YI reflecting strong
underlying economic activity. We believe
that these high frequency indicators
should auger well for a commercial and
of segmented
by GST rationalization the automo sector
has seen a significant uptick in sales.
According to retail sales data based on
WAN registration, the auto industry
recorded a growth of 19.5% for quarter 3
2026 resulting in a total of 9.4 million
vehicles sold.
Within this private car had seen a
growth of 19.3%
translating to 1.3 million vehicles. The
two-heer segment grew by 19.2%
with the 7 million vehicles whereas
commercial vehicles grew by 22.2%.
with 1.1 million vehicle being sold.
Interestingly, the overall growth in the
vehicle sales is the highest in last 12
quarters. To add to it, this growth is
more broad-based as tier three cities
and beyond have demonstrated faster
growth in both private car and two-heer
segments. This is also coraborated by
strong growth of 28.8% in tractor sales
for the quarter. Overall, the
acceleration in new vehicle sales for
the quarter has also led to a 7.7%
growth for calendar year 2025 with a
28.1 million units being sold.
The landmark decision of exemption of
GST on retail health insurance has
significantly improved affordability and
increased awareness.
The industry has passed on the complete
benefit of GST exemptions to the end
consumers.
This has led to an increase in policy
uptake as more customers are seeing
health seeking healthcare protection.
Here too, the growth in retail health
appears to be broad-based across markets
and it's supported by a surge in
firsttime buyers especially for tier 2
and tier three cities which is a
positive for this sector.
On the regulatory front, the government
of India took a significant step during
the quarter by introducing
forward-looking reforms in the insurance
laws with the passage of Sapka Bima Saki
amendment of insurance laws bill 2025.
While most of these amendments will have
far-reaching effects on the insurance
sector over time, a few important
changes pertaining to the insurance act
are as follows. Foreign investment in an
Indian insurance company has enhanced
from 74% to 100% thereby supporting
capital inflows enabling provisions in
the amendment act to facilitate business
other than traditional insurance
underwriting and distribution thereby
allowing insurers to offer holistic risk
management services.
Simplification of provisions relating to
investments of assets.
We are excited about these changes and
we do believe that this should be
structurally positive and would
accelerate the growth and development of
the insurance sector. This will also
facilitate ease of doing business and
provide better protection and risk
management solutions to the policy
holders.
In another significant reform in
November 2025, the government of India
formally made effective four new central
labor codes including the code on social
security 2020. Consequent to this
benefits like graduity, leave and cash
etc. paid on basic salary are now
required to be paid basis the new
broader definition of wage.
We believe this changes should translate
into a more resilient workforce and
strengthen employee security over time.
This change has a one-time impact on the
financials which will be covered by
Gopal in his section.
Let me now dwell upon the industry
performance for the period ended 31st
December 2025.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 8.7% for 9 month 2026.
Excluding crop and mass cell segment,
the GDPI growth at 13.3 growth stood at
13.3% for the period 9 month 2026.
Speaking on specific segments within the
industry, commercial segment recorded a
healthy growth of 14.8 8% for 9 month
2026 and 16.3% for quarter 3 2026.
This growth led by strong momentum in
the fire line which grew at 20.1% for
our 9 month 2026.
As mentioned above, this is driven by an
increase in capex particularly in areas
such as roads, railways and renewable
energy.
The motor segment grew at 8.9% in 9
month 2026.
compared to 7.6% in H1 2026. For quarter
3 financial year 2026, the growth stood
at 10.9% supported by festive season
demand and the positive impact of GST
rationalization. Health segment grew at
14.2%
for 9 months 2026 with a strong momentum
of 27.6% 6% growth in quarter 3 of 2026
led by retail health which grew at 33.6%
and group health growth of 23.1%
underscoring strong demand across the
segment.
On the other hand, industry combined
ratio worsened from 113.3%
in H1 of 2025 to 119.2% 2% in H1 of 2026
indicating continued underwriting
pressure. During the same period, ICL
core moved from 103.2%
in financial year 2025 to 104.0%
in H1 of 2026, reinforcing a superior
financial performance through
disciplined underwriting.
The motor line of business remains a key
area of stress with the industry core
increasing from 124.8% 8% in H1 of 2025
to 128.5%
in H1 of 2026.
IC Lumbar demonstrated better portfolio
management in motor insurance with the
combined ratio improving from 108 to
106.9%
during the same period.
I will now proceed to present our
company's performance across key
business segments.
For 9 month 2026, gross domestic pre
premium income of the company grew by
3.6% compared to industry growth of 8.7%
for the same period.
Within this for quarter 3 2026 the
company reported a premium growth of
13.3% compared to industry growth of
11.5%
thereby improving its market share from
8.1% for quarter 3 2025 to 8.3% for
quarter 3 2026
for December 2025 in particular the
company's growth in GDPI was 15.1% in
comparison to the industry growth of
14.4% 4%.
Excluding cross crop and mass health,
the company recorded a growth of 7.5%
during 9 month financial year 2026
against the industry growth of 13.3%.
Within this for quarter 3 2025, the
company record a growth of 16.4%
as against the industry growth of 20.1%.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 7.4%
and 6.8% for quarter 3 2026 and 9 month
respectively. While the industry grew by
16.3% for quarter 3 2026 and 14.8% for 9
month 2026.
We continue to be focused on delivering
profitable growth through discipline and
underwriting, prudent risk selection and
portfolio diversification. resulting in
the growth of fire segment by 18.8% in
quarter 3 2026 driven by 27.4% growth in
theme segment.
Further, the company delivered a 19.3%
growth in fire compared to 15.8 industry
growth for the month of December 2025.
In the engineering segment, our growth
stood at 15.2% 2% and 13.3% for quarter
3 2026 and 9 month 2026 respectively.
While the industry during the same
period grew by 11.5%
and 12.9% respectively. This led to we
attaining leadership position position
in engineering segment for the 9 month
2026.
On the other side for 9 month 2026 the
company's growth for marine cargo and
liability segment was not in line with
the industry growth on on account of
portfolio rationalization. However, we
continue to maintain our leadership
position in these lines.
In motor segment for 9 month the company
record a growth of 5% whereas the
industry view by 8.9%.
While I while our growth in H1 of 2026
was only 2.2 2%. A rebound was observed
in Q3 2026 driven by an underlying
buoyancy in new motor vehicle sales.
Consequently, the motor segment grew by
9.3% in Q3 2026 supported by a strong
growth of 16.1% in December 2025.
Despite heightened competitive intensity
in the recent quarters, we remain
focused on profitable growth driven by
continuous expansion across distribution
channels and a more granular portfolio
segmentation.
Importantly, the company continues to
maintain it leadership position in the
motor segment with the market share of
10.7% for 9 months 2026.
The company's portfolio motor portfolio
mix of private car, two-wheer and
commercial vehicle stood at 53.6,
25.8% and 20.6% respectively for 9 month
financial year 2026.
In the health segment, the company grew
by 42% and up 13.8% for quarter 3 2026
and for 9 month 2026 respectively as
against the industry growth of 27.6 6%
and 14.2% for quarter 3 financial year
2026 and 9 month 2026 respectively.
Our health business delivered a robust
growth of 85.8%
in quarter 3 2026 and 44.8%
in 9 month 2026 significantly
outperforming the industry growth of
33.6% 6% in quarter 3 and 16.5% for 9
month 2026.
Our growth was fueled by new to industry
customer growth of 1.7x for quarter 3
2026 and 1.4 times for 9 month 2026.
Thus, our market share increases to 4%
in 9 month 2026 compared to 3.2% for the
same period in the previous year. And
for quarter 3 2026, our market share has
increased to 4.5%
from 3.2% for the same period in
previous year. The strong performance
has also been driven by sustained
investment and strengthening our retail
distribution capabilities across
channels.
The group health segment registered a
growth of 26.6%
and 5.9% for quarter 3 2026 and 9 month
2026 respectively. While the industry
grew by 23.1% for quarter 3 2026 and
12.6% for 9 month 2026.
I would now like to apprise you of
certain strategic initiatives that
continue to drive operational excellence
and customer sensit centricity across
the organization.
The one hour one call center initiative
continues to deliver strong momentum in
the company's transition towards a
digital first do-ityourself servicing
model. In December over 60% of the total
service engagements were managed
digitally as against 38% only for April
2025. This was possible due to our AI AI
interventions through various bots which
has helped customers in adopting DIY
service modes.
This has led to improved turnaround
times, service consistency and increased
productivity. Our differentiated service
desk initiatives which we can which we
had spoken about in a previous call have
resulted in increase of our call center
NPS to 73 in Q3 of 2026 from 60 in Q1 of
financial year 2026.
Building on a one is one digital
framework, we continue to take positive
strides toward offering a seamless and
omni channel experience across our
website and the take care platform. As
you might recall, the ILCare app was
initially launched to provide a
continuum of care for our health
insurance customers. Over time, the app
has continuously evolved with new
functionaries and features, making it a
comprehensive one-stop solution for
service and sales across multiple retail
product lines.
The app has now crossed 19.7 million
downloads as of December 31st, 2025,
reflecting growing customer engagement
and dig digital adoption.
The customer registered the the company
registered a GWP of 3.54 billion for 9
month 2026 from the ILC care app as
against 1.45 billion for the same period
last year. Take care has also made
significant progress in addressing key
customer service requirements and
delivering a seamless insurance
experience. Just to highlight for Trip
Secure Plus, our premier travel
insurance product, customers can now
independently manage claims, policy
cancellations, extensions, and
modifications through the app. These
enhancements have enabled 93%
of services, service requests to be
processed on DIY basis without the need
for manual intervention,
leading to a corresponding reduction in
support call volumes. Notably 79% of
claim intimation for trip secure plus in
December 2025 were also initiated
through take care app as compared to 22%
in July 2025.
In order to continually enhance our
efficiency levels in motor claims, we
have expanded our cashless garage
network from 13,600 plus garages in
quarter 3 2025 to 15,000 garages in
quarter 3 2026.
75.2%
of our nonEM claims for quarter 3 2026
were serviced at PPN up from 73.6 in
quarter 3 2025 leading to a enhanced
customer experience.
In the retail segment 99.6% of our total
claims were paid within 30 days and for
motor insurance own damage segment 96.8%
of our claims were paid within 30 days
for the period ended 9 month 2026.
As a result, our NPS for H1 2026 for
health claims stood at 70 and for motor
claims stood at 69, reinforcing our
position as a customer centric
organization.
In conclusion, the domestic macro
environment remains supportive with
broad-based consumption showing healthy
momentum. We remain focused on building
a sustainable long-term franchise
anchored in the strength of our
technology processes and service
architecture. Through our one team
initiative, we continue to sharpen
execution, drive consistency, and
deliver customer outcomes at scale. We
are well positioned to convert a more
supportive demand environment into a
steady highquality growth while
maintaining discipline in underwriting,
service delivery and operating
efficiency. I will now request Gopal to
take you through the financial numbers
for the period 9 month 2026. Uh
>> thanks Njie and uh good evening to each
one of you. I will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter and 9
months. We have uploaded the results
presentation on our website. You all can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers. Uh with effect from
October 1, 2024, long-term products are
accounted on a 1 byN basis as mandated
by our regulator. Please refer to the
investor presentation on slide 16 for a
much more detailed information on
comparison of financials on N and 1 byN
basis. Uh now let me update on GDPI
numbers. Please note these numbers are
on 1 byN basis. The GDP of the company
was at uh 213.72 billion rupees in 9
months current year as against rupees
206.23 billion in 9 months FI25 a growth
of 3.6% 6% as against the industry
growth of 8.7%.
GDP of the company was at 70 billion
70.41 billion in Q3 FI26 as against
rupees 62.14 billion in Q3 FI25 a growth
of 13.3% as against the industry growth
of 11.5%.
Resulting in our market share to grow
from 8.1% in quarter 3 last year to 8.3%
in quarter 3 of the current year. On the
retail side of the business, GDP of the
motor segment was at rupes 33.99 billion
in Q3 FI26 as against rupes 31.09
billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 9.3%.
The advanced premium for motor segment
was at 41.26 billion rupees as at
December 31, 2025 as against rupes 39.13
billion as at September 30, 2025.
GDP of the health segment was at rupes
20.44 44 in Q3 this year as against
rupes 14.53 billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 40.6%.
Within this our retail health segment
registered a robust growth of 85.8%.
During the same period GDP of our
commercial line was at rupes 15.72
billion in Q3 FI26 as against rupes
14.63 billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 7.4%. Our agent
which includes the point of sale
distribution count was 1 lak 50,458
as at December 31 2025 up from 14748
as at September 30 2025. Our combined
ratio on 1 by n basis was 104.2%
in 9 months current year as against
102.9%
in 9 months last year. On an N basis,
our combined ratio was 103.1% in the
current year as against 102.8%
in 9 months last year. The combined
ratio on again 1 by N for this quarter 3
current year was 104.5%.
as against 102.7% in Q3 last year. Again
on an end basis for this year quarter 3
combined ratio was 103.1
as against 102.3 in Q3 FI25.
We have been talking about the impact of
CAT losses. If one was to exclude the
impact of CAT losses of rupees.84
billion in 9 months current year and 94
billion in 9 months of last year. The
combined ratio on a 1 by n basis was
103.7%
and 102.3% respectively. The same
numbers on an n basis was 102.6% and
102.2% respectively.
Uh now coming to the quarter excluding
the impact of cat losses of rupees.1
billion in Q3 current year the combined
ratio on 1xn was 104.3
and the same numbers on an n basis was
103%.
There were no CAT losses in Q3 FI25 and
as mentioned by Sanji in his opening
remarks excluding the impact of wage
code of rupees.55
billion our combined ratio on a 1 byN
basis for 9 months current year and
quarter 3 current year was 103.9%
and 103.5%
respectively.
On a n basis our combined ratio
excluding the wage code wage code impact
was 102.8 8% and 102.2% for 9 months and
Q3 respectively. Our investment assets
during the quarter rose to rupes 582.96
billion as at December 31, 2025 up from
rupes 562 billion as at September 30,
2025. Our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 3.6 times at December 31,
as against 3.57 at September 30, 2025.
Investment income was at rupes 37.57
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupes 33.73 billion in 9 months
last year. On a quarterly basis,
investment income was at rupees 12.19
billion in Q3 current year as against
rupes 11.21 billion in Q3 last year. Our
capital gains net of impairment
investment assets stood at rupes 9.33
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupees 7.96 billion in 9 months
last year. Capital gains stood at rupes
3.17 billion in quarter 3 current year
as compared to rupees 2.76 billion in Q3
last year. On a 1 byN basis, our PBT
grew by 10.8% at rupees 29.41 billion in
9 months current year as against rupees
26.53 billion in 9 months last year on
an again for the quarter on a 1 by basis
PBT grew by 9.4%
for the current quarter as against
rupees 9.6 6 billion in Q3 last year.
Consequently, on a 1 byN basis, PAT grew
by 11.3%
at rupes 22.225 billion in 9 months
current year as against rupes 19.99
billion in 9M last year. The same
numbers on an end basis for profit after
tax grew by 13.8% at rupes 22.22 billion
in 9 months current year as against
rupees 19.53 billion in 9 months last
year. On a oneby basis, fat degrrew by
9.1% at 6.59 billion in Q3 current year
from 7.24 billion in Q3 last year. Again
coming back to N basis PAT remained
flattish at 6.8 billion in Q3 current
year from 6.79 billion in Q3 last last
year excluding the impact of wage code
uh on a 1 byN basis PAT was rupes 22.67
67 billion in 9 months current year and
rupes 7 billion in Q3 current year
registering a growth of 13.4% and a
degrowth of 3.3% respectively. The same
numbers on an end basis PAT was rupees
22.64 billion for 9 months current year
and rupees 7.21 billion in Q3 of this
quarter registering a growth of 15.9%
and 6.3% respectively.
Coming to ROE on a 1 byN basis it was
19.5% in 9 months as against 20.8% in 9
months last year. ROE for the quarter 3
current year was 16.5% as against 21.5%
in Q3 FI25 excluding the wage code
impact on a 1 byN basis ROE was 19.8%
and 17.5% in 9 months and Q3 of the
current year respectively. Solveny ratio
was at 2.69 69 times at December 31,
2025 as against 2.73 times at September
30, 2025 continued to be higher than the
minimum regulatory requirement of 1.5
times. As I conclude, I would like to
state that uh we are all aligned with
our ethos of driving profitable growth,
consistent and sustainable value
creation for all our stakeholders while
ensuring that the interest of the policy
holders are in the forefront at all
times. I'd like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
now be happy to take any questions that
you have. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
with the question and answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and then one on their
touchstone phone.
If you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles.
>> Our first question comes from the line
of Supraatim Duta from Jeff. Please go
ahead.
>> Hi. Um, thanks for the opportunity. My
first question is on the labor codes.
Um, you know, we understand that you
know there is a 50 crore impact from you
know the labor code changes. Just wanted
to understand what proportion of this is
recurring versus what proportion of this
was one time. You know that was the
first question. Secondly, you know,
coming to growth now, you know, despite
the GST tailwinds, um, you know, the
growth even on the motor side, if I see
has been, you know, slower than what the
industry has, uh, witnessed and I do
understand that, you know, competition
has been elevated. But you know the
regulator at the regulatory level has
taken multiple steps you know be it
expense of management guidelines or you
know discussions with industry you know
to reduce the competitive intensity or
bring in some bit of rationality yet we
are you know not able to see that
happen. So from here you know if I'm
taking a 2 to three year view what will
you know drive growth in the motor
segment for a player like you which
already has 10 11% market share you know
that's you know if you could throw some
light on that you know that would be
very helpful and lastly on the motor TP
loss ratio uh I do understand last time
there was a TP release
uh but uh you know this time it seems to
be a more normalized loss ratio um could
we assume that you know the reserve
releases would hold and you know there
is no further release that that would
come in the fourth quarter or you know
could there be further releases that
would come in the fourth quarter if you
could throw some light on the res but
that would also be helpful. Thank you.
>> Thanks. Thanks. Thanks for those
questions. uh on the first one uh so far
as the labor code is concerned obviously
uh uh uh the impact of 55 crores uh in
that sense is one time because it's
primarily the liability resulting from
an actual evaluation uh for the past
service uh cost uh in so far as uh uh
wages is concerned. Having said that,
obviously this code is also evolving. Uh
so hence to that extent we will have to
see if there are any more incremental
guidelines or rules that are that come
into existence. But at this point of
time this is whatever has been released
thus far. This impact of 55 crores is uh
what is the past service uh cost uh
which is more which is a complete impact
that we have taken in the financials of
quarter 3 and 9 months. And if you have
seen also the disclosure that we have
made uh there is an element of roughly
about 17 crores. This is the amount of
unamotized cost uh which will kind of
get uh amotized over the next 3 years
and in line with again the acturial
report. Uh those are the two numbers in
so far as uh the impact of wage code is
concerned. 55 crores is more a one-time
impact in the financials. 17 crores of
amotized cost is something that will get
amotized over the next uh 3 years. So
that's in response to the first one. On
the response to the third question,
motor third party loss ratios. Um I
think I will keep uh keep ritating this
uh what we have told the market is um
overall motor loss ratio range that we
have spoken is between 65 to 67%. And if
you look at uh the 9month numbers and
that is something that we keep urging
that you should keep looking at year-to-
date numbers than more quarterly
outcomes. The 9month numbers for the
current year motor overall stands at
about 66.3%. This is both own damage and
third party put together. So it's kind
of pretty much playing out in line with
the range that one has spoken about and
hence to that extent uh uh we are quite
happy with the way how things have
progressed. To your point on any uh
impact of reserving etc etc. uh again we
will keep uh stressing on the fact that
there has been no change in any of our
actual assumptions and therefore to that
extent it is not that we have done
anything specific whether it was in the
context of last year or even for the
matter of fact when you look at the
numbers from a current year perspective
um so that's in response to the uh third
one and on the second one uh I will
maybe Sanjiv
>> yeah I will just uh so on the motor part
uh clearly first up we are extremely
excited with the positive environ ment
that has got created as I was giving the
briefing the quarter three numbers the
growth in number of vehicles across
private car two-heer as well as CV which
was which has been more than 19% the
highest in last 12 quarters is a very
very good sign uh this increase in
number has also come with the GST
rationalization which made the vehicles
cheaper and with that coming through we
had to also realign what is required and
we also spoke about in terms of how the
combine for the market has moved in
motor from 124 which was hard enough to
128. So the realignment was a very key
piece which is what we as an
organization has done. Uh consequent to
this what we are seeing is the growth of
December in particular where we have
exceeded the market expectations. We
remain very positively driven overall as
to what motor holds for us. We've closed
the year with a 10.7% market share. uh
probably a loss of uh point4 or
thereabouts as to what we had 9 months
but as we close the positivity with
which we expect even Q4 numbers to build
up on the new sales would drive growth
for us because that is the combination
which we are probably best at
overall from an environment standpoints
we do see consumption playing a big role
and in that upward mobility of a
two-heer customer seeking private car
and thereabout also is becoming very
clear also So one more point which bell
for us is we've been a distributionled
company and the growth is broad-based
which is where they see that we are t3
and about where the market growth also
is coming it again is a big positive for
us and it will help us to drive what we
want to drive as an agenda. So we are
overall on motor uh very positively
placed but the realignment in wake of
what the intensity is seen is something
which is warranted and we have always
maintained that we'll never shy away
from taking those calls but a range
mount 10.7% market share where we stand
we are pretty much involved as a number
one player as a topmost player we are
also very aware of the responsibility
that we carry in the motor segment in
particular So
>> that's very helpful. Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Your next question comes from the line
of Sankit Koda from Aendos Spark. Please
go ahead.
>> Uh yeah thank you for the opportunity.
Uh uh you see the retail health growth
85 or 86 odd percentage in the third
quarter. Um honestly it has the
unwinding portion of last year too. So
if if I do end to end comparison uh
which which is more like to like so so
so the uh can you just uh spell out the
growth how how the retail health has
panned out uh if you look on end end to-
end basis
we not separately calling that out so
honestly uh to that extent I think what
we would say is that uh what we are very
excited is what I think Sanjiv responded
even on motor I think the underlying
demand on ground is kind of pretty much
playing out consequent to some of the
rationalizations that have happened in
the context of uh GST uh that we have
kind of talked about even in the last
quarter and and hence to that extent uh
one would say that the growth is very
very uh uh exciting and hence to that
extent while it does have an impact uh
but um honestly our sense is uh I think
broadly even if I were to kind of uh
give a number even on an end basis I
think that growth would be more or less
around the same range of between 80 to
85%. So hence it doesn't kind of change
much uh which is what we had said what
we are very very excited is more the
underlying impact momentum than looking
at numbers whether on an end basis or a
one by end basis
>> yeah and also you know we talking about
if you look at the numbers you've gone
on 80% plus in all three months October
November and December uh so very clearly
uh the need for differentiating that and
talking as it is it's not a easy
commentary we talking one by n by n I
for you to listen on audio itself is a
challenge. I can tell you probably you
can make more sense when you have the
script in hand. Uh but this growth and
what we have been doing over sustained
quarter also is reflected in the market
share which has increased to 4.5% in Q3.
Uh which is which clearly speaks about
the underlying momentum that uh the team
has been able to build. Uh and if your
question is do you see this momentum
probably playing out even in quarter 4?
My answer would be every reason to
believe and it's dri and it's again
driven by a very good demand across
markets. So there is a play and we have
a product and we have a team which is
capable of driving this uh transition.
If you ask the beginning of the year did
we expect a uh 4 and a half% of market
share my answer would have been probably
it would have been a shade lower than
that. So there is tailwind which is also
helping us look uh better than what we
could have been but would we have been
far probably would have been 4%. So it's
it's pretty much there and we are well
set. So we at the right place at the
right time uh as far as health is
concerned.
>> Uh essentially this this I mean honestly
this growth is little extraordinary even
if I looked it from the industry um
standard point of view. Is it any
particular channel or or you which were
way not present in a particular channel
now exploring the channel has
contributed to the growth.
>> So I that that I can explain you that I
can that's what your question was. So
see the product elevate was last year
July. Okay. So we had started doing well
in that and that renewal base also comes
and gets added to the book. So
mathematically plus supported by the
tailwind there's an answer to that part.
I mean I'm definitely not saying that
85% of the growth that will continue
over quarters and quarters. So
mathematically speaking the retention of
a product and the quality product is
there then you get good customers and
the retention also is very high and so
there is that part which is helping us
to drive this kind of a growth circuit.
>> Understood. But but any any new channel
which contributed like like like maybe
you were not present in one
>> pretty of course our agency channel has
opened up significantly and we able to
attract lot more channels. So agency is
uh driving this growth but at the same
time we were on website so we've been
pretty uh across channels uh but the
contribution percentage per se of what
was there would not have gone through a
significant change if you look at the
distribution pattern. So we have seen
this growth across uh channels uh uh
some
>> okay uh no Sanj the reason I'm asking is
that
>> anyone anyone banker for that matter
>> understood understood the reason I'm
asking this question is that is is our
payout structure to the distributor is
more skewed on n basis rather than one
by n basis and given the
>> no no no we have absolute clarity that
even if it's long-term uh what we will
do is what comes with one by as a as a
as a team for us we continue to operate
strictly on those guidelines. Okay.
>> Okay. Understood. So, so basically
commission payouts are also on basis.
>> Sorry to interrupt.
>> Yeah. Yeah. On that. Yes.
>> Okay. Understood. Understood. Thanks.
>> Yeah. Madam so it would be
differentiated to that extent that one
first year would be something and then
second and third year that obviously is
the case but it is distributed basis.
>> Understood. Understood. Thank you. If if
I squeeze in one more sorry
>> sorry to interrupt. Okay sir. May we
request to return to the queue for
followup questions as there are several
other participants waiting for their
>> Yeah. Yes sir.
>> Thank you so much. Our next question
comes from the line of pre Jane from
Motil. Please go ahead.
>> Uh yeah. Hi everyone. Uh a couple of
questions.
>> Um just a couple of questions. Firstly
on the motor side uh Sanji we've seen a
tremendous growth in volumes and what
I've understood is there is
premiumization trends as well. uh in
spite of that uh the uh premium growth
for the industry has uh has a decent gap
between the volume growth of the
industry as well as the uh the premium
growth what we have seen right uh so in
that sense what is causing that
disparity and have you seen any further
pricing aggression uh in Q3 with respect
to uh you know motor OD premiums given
that uh you know it was anticipated that
the growth would be there and uh the
competition intensities increase. That
my first question and second question is
in terms of retail health could you uh
give us some uh qualitative or some
numbers as around uh as to what is the
kind of growth that is driving the the
new customers that are coming uh what
are they coming at you know what kind of
some assures they are coming and also
the existing customers are they scaling
up the summer assured and maintaining
their premium levels or what's the kind
of uh trajectory that we are seeing Yes.
>> Yeah. Okay. So on the uh motor side P uh
clearly if you see the growth has been
uh broad-based uh and you see small car
these small hatchback cars being sold
far higher uh than any other car. So the
the volume growth may not necessarily
translate into a equivalent uh growth in
premium for the industry. And also what
is to be noted is that this growth also
is fueled by the rationalization which
happened from 28 to 18%. Which itself
led to an impact on the yield per
vehicle going down. So it's the combined
uh thing and that is where the
realignment also had to be done by us as
a team to ensure that what we pick up
overall uh from the market uh with
respect to our own motor portfolio and
also we spoke about how the H1
is uh you know seeing the combined ratio
getting that's to answer the competitive
intensity that you're speaking about the
motor combined in 124 and.5 and
thereabouts had very little room to go
further down. It moved down to 128 and
if that is the kind of you know
development that comes in there is no
reason to believe that the competition
intensity has gone down and at the same
time you spoke about specific players
coming and coming out. Frankly speaking
our journey is very secular. you know we
we've got a decent understanding and we
back ourselves in terms of what we are
picking up and what we do want to do in
this motor segment in particular uh we
are uh and we have always maintained
that we are very comfortable walking
away what is not making basic sense on
the ro level for motor so we do
understand we are willing to play the uh
you know game if there's an roe that
comes through even if it's on an
elevated combine but not in a in a in in
a random manner where we just keep
acquiring because there's an opportunity
available. So, so that kind of a
discipline is what drives us and that's
why when the industry has moved from a
124 to 128 our combine actually improved
by some a percentage and some few more
basis points in that H1 period also. So
it's it's to be taken in collaboration
while maintaining market leadership. So
uh uh further pricing aggression very
little room but we maintained that over
last couple of quarters but we are very
unfaced because our journey of how we
can slice and dice and do what makes
sense what makes sense for us uh we we
would back ourselves and we are very
confident that we'll be able to deliver
what is warranted for us as a company
on uh is that pre I hope this answers
what you're seeking on motors and and
more
on this
>> uh and no TPI no TPI is another part
which I must add uh to say which has
made the uh yield look what it is we
have been always expecting it but it's
not come through as yet
okay just one thing on that motor before
you kind of answer the retail health uh
the hatchbacks and the smaller cars uh
would you say that g given a lot of them
could be the first-time buyers uh
structurally and given you you have a
large history of long history of data on
the same kind of vehicles being sold and
first-time buyers would you say that the
loss ratios or could be higher on this
segment going ahead of course we can we
can discuss in detail but the uh the the
long answer in I'll make it short and
say the cars have also started coming
with much better safety features the
road also has changed so there is a lot
more the challenge systems are getting
digitized the uh overlay in terms of
investigating what's gone wrong because
there are cameras everywhere across the
country the surveillance has increased
so there's a lot more pluses there are
lot more minuses I'm not saying it uh
and these are all the factors that we
are able to use uh to drive what we want
to drive as a team and that's the USP
that we carry right so we wouldn't be
too faced by it uh and if we do see
segment
going out of hand I think our ability to
take a cause probably ahead of the
market is what uh is the what is what
differentiates us uh as a team. I hope
again I'm able to put across what I'm
saying.
>> Yeah.
>> And on the retail health
>> yeah on the retail health clearly we
have seen far more you know awareness. I
think this GST card besides of course
making it more affordable has been the
biggest marketing
you know to make the individuals and
their families to realize that health
insurance is critical and as a trend to
be very honest we do see some insured
increasing significantly we see bulk of
our customers in the range of 7 and a
half to 10 lakhs some insured so which
is a big positive also to just share
with all of you whenever a customer
picks up a higher sum insured their
ability to retain and be with us is much
higher because the quality of the
customer is much better. So yes, it's a
big plus for us uh uh as a company.
>> Thank you so much. Wish you all the
best.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Your next question comes from
the line of Avin Singh from MK Global.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi, good evening. Uh thanks for
the opportunity. Uh so couple of
question. The first one is uh looking at
the impact of 1 by n in terms of a
combined ratios is it kind of a fair
assumption that the your multi-year
product has seen a very very strong
growth if you can sort of a provide some
color I mean within your retail health
what is the multi-year uh premium share
so that's one second uh kind of a you
know that now we are kind of have seen 9
10 months of the year uh so for 27 Seven
uh uh if I have missed I don't know uh
you can provide some kind of uh you know
guidance on growth as well as on
combined and related partly in motor
third party should we expect uh you know
by the time your Q4 some reserve
releases given that I mean your I mean
where your reserving are sitting or kind
of a reserve releases India by 22 to 24
is still pretty minimal. So is it kind
of a you know fair to assume that okay
the Q4 should see some motor TP.
>> Yeah so Ain uh I think I'll go it on the
reverse way. Uh so motor third party I
think obviously uh yeah uh I think as an
industry we all have been kind of
waiting for the price announcement. Uh
so we'll wait and see by the time we
announce uh results for the next
quarter. Hopefully we will see where we
where we land. Um so we will keep all of
you updated on that. uh on the second
piece on uh what is it that we can
expect for the next year. I think this
is something that we had spoken even in
uh as in last quarter as in to say that
I think given the strong growth momentum
that we see kind of getting rebound back
to us. Uh what we have always maintained
is at a uh at a top line or from a
growth standpoint we have tried to see
if we can be 100 to 200 basis points at
a company level better than the industry
growth numbers. uh this is cutting
across all lines and uh and that is
exactly what possibly you would have
seen uh getting exhibited in quarter 3
uh for us uh in terms of where we our
growth where we the industry growth and
even more specifically if you would have
seen even for the month of December I
think we have had an outperformance with
the overall industry numbers so
therefore that's something that we would
endeavor even as we head into given the
strong growth momentum that one is
seeing on ground and hence to that
extent that is what we would kind of
pencil in in terms of trying to continue
to gain in the incremental market share
on combined more important than the
combined I think what we have largely
spoken is to try and see if we can
continue to sustain delivering roses in
that in that range of 18 to 20% even if
you would have seen the numbers for the
9 months it's been roughly around 19%
thereabout so hence to that extent uh in
that range of 18 to 20% so that's
something that is something is what we
would look forward again when you look
at uh how we would want to play out even
for the next year uh from an ROE
standpoint uh to your first point I I
think it is a high singledigit number in
terms of the proportion of long-term uh
uh premiums vly the total premium that
we underwrite. Um but um I think the
only thing that we would keep urging is
uh I think even as I was as I was
reading the transcript I did realize
there are so many numbers on an end and
a one by n basis across various
parameters. Um so hence to that extent
if you ask us ideally on a consist this
will actually kind of continue for even
maybe for the next three quarters
because while uh while quarter three of
this year onwards now we everything is
on a one by end but still there has
always be a factor of the first question
that was being asked in terms of what is
the impact of acured of last year in
this quarter and so on and so forth. So
hence to that extent a far better
reflection is to keep looking at numbers
on an end basis and there if you would
have seen our combined for quarter 3 has
actually been better. I think if you
look at quarter 3 of last year our
combined was roughly about 102.3%.
And this number on an end basis for
quarter 3 the current year is also so
because there I just want to interject
and make this point and we had said that
also when one by came in as a company uh
we don't want to confuse at any point of
time economic value to accounting you
know we very clear so we have uh uh in
all our conversations with our team and
key personnels who are involved uh we
only discuss on end basis because that
is the true value which will get
embedded in the what comes because of
the uh accounting part is just an
outcome for us and that is the real
value uh you know value that we can add
even our budgets for that matter if you
have to share are all taken on end basis
uh uh because that's how portfolio can
be picked up in the right manner and
even cash flows can get generated
otherwise the tendency to make it
shorter and shorter would erode value
over long term sorry Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> Thanks.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Nidesh from Invest. Please
go ahead.
>> Uh thanks for the opportunity. Uh so can
you share the share of uh new uh in the
motor segment? What is the new and what
is uh old vehicles?
I'm trying to understand whether the
market share trends are more uh the
market share trends how they are shaping
up in both these segments are we have we
lost market share in the new side that
is reflecting into lower growth or or
it's in both both segment our market
share trends are broadly similar
>> so so n just for the benefit of all of
you I'll give you two numbers uh one is
in terms of mix for quarter 3 new is
roughly about 35% renewal is about 65
uh and if you see this numbers for 9
months new is about 33 and renewal book
is about 67. So in that sense relatively
for quarter 3 uh the mix is about uh 35
and 65. But more important than the mix
if you ask us I think the point that we
have been talking about given the
underlying growth momentum going play
out with respect to new vehicle sales
and there again in the same order as in
I will give you Q3 numbers first. Our
new growth has been 12.4%.
Uh and our old growth has been 7.7%.
translating to an overall growth in
quarter 3 in motor for a set about 9.3.
These same numbers if you look at it on
a 9month basis the new growth was has
been 2.5%. The renewal growth has been
6.2 translated an overall growth of 5%.
So this is exactly the point that we
have been talking about. I think what we
are seeing is clearly an underlying
strong growth momentum coming coming in
with respect to new vehicle sales.
Having said that that does not mean that
for us uh renewals/ retentions are not
important. I think that's equally very
very important. But what we have been
able to leverage is a combination of
both the underlying growth momentum with
respect to new vehicle sales and then of
course the continued focus on improving
retentions as well.
>> Yeah absolutely and uh the fact that the
9 month average is uh when we talk about
new is 2.5 and old is 6.2 Q2 while for
the Q3 uh the number goes the other way
where the new is the growth has been led
by new and as in the past Gopal has been
briefly new has its own set of expenses
that comes but a blatio and that
consequent to that it will have its uh
impact but will have a long-term value
allocation for us as a company. uh in
the past for the quarters that we done
always it was driven by old growth and
if you go back to our scripts that we
have said we have said our growth is
driven by old so that's a big transition
it's a big plus overall for us and we
have been able to obviously garner more
new uh in the market uh which has helped
us to get this kind of a growth
>> sure secondly if you can share the loss
ratio in health uh segment wise
>> yeah I was just waiting for somebody to
But anyway uh so uh on uh on uh group
health uh I'll first give the quarter
three numbers and then the 9 month
numbers. First I'll give you the Q3 and
9 month numbers of last year. Group
health uh last year was about 97.2
and uh this number for 9 months of last
year was 97.7.
uh the same group health numbers for
quarter 3 this year was 90.7
and 9 month numbers is 93.2
for retail indemnity that's the other
number that generally gets asked for uh
this again quarter 3 last year retail
indemnity loss ratio was 65%.
This number 9 months was 69.1.
For the current year quarter 3, retail
indemnity loss ratios are 63.1.
9 month loss ratio numbers are 67.3. So
again if you look at uh what we have
been telling the market is on corporate
health or group health generally we have
maintained that we are quite comfortable
running at the book with the mid90s.
That's being the that's the threshold
that we have spoken about on the
corporate health and that's exactly how
it has played out on a 9-month basis and
even retail health I think the range
that we have generally spoken to the
market is to see if we are able to run
the book at a range between 65 to 70%. I
think what we are quite excited with is
the way how the growth in the book has
played out and the fact that we have
kind of largely seen maybe couple of
renewal cycles play through on the new
product that we kind of launched last
year. I think the good news is I think
the experience that you are seeing on
ground I think is kind of pretty much
holding on to the assumptions that we
had kind of pencileled in when we kind
of launched this. So those are the two
numbers uh that I would kind of uh give
give away to all.
>> Sure. And lastly that on the health side
we are showing very strong growth but
from a longerterm perspective how should
we uh how do we plan to manage the issue
of uh uh old lives getting subsidized by
the new lives and that lead to uh loss
ratio deteriorating over a long period
of time. Uh currently we are still a
young company on the health side but as
the growth matures let's say five year
down the line how what is the strategy
to manage the overall loss ratio.
So two three data points uh one is that
the penetration of retail in health in
the country overall is 5%. Okay, most of
us end up looking at group health as a
funible thing for retail cover that
awareness is building up and there's a
long play available and it's also linked
to the purchasing power if we believe
that the uh GDP growth the purchasing
power the income tax curve the GST all
are leaving this there's a significant
road available where the uh growth of
new to the insurance or new to
protection uh will keep seeing a
significant in uh uh traction and also
as loss rats picks up which is very real
and you're absolutely spot on but at the
same time the expense and the commission
of acquisition also goes down. So there
is a counterplay that comes in and uh
the the aging book in terms of how it
evolves and develops better medical
solutioning all of that what comes into
play we can talk about that when we meet
again but there is a play available and
that's why we see a uh future as we you
know as we go about it
and there is of course and just to add
to it there's a good uh preventive play
that will also become a critical factor
for each one of us in our life. So if
there was a and as a company we would uh
be very actively involved. There's so
much more available and through I'll
take care which has got good traction in
real terms. Uh we do believe that we
will play a significant role. Right now
it's all setting the policy and
admission is how we interact but that
also is progressively changing. uh there
is a good highway available uh and it's
not that sitting in our room we don't
play out and simulate as to how this
portfolio will behave uh 2 years 3 years
5 years down the line these are part of
actual actial modelings and we are well
aware of it
>> sure sir that's it from my side thank
you
>> thank you thank you
>> thank you next question comes from the
line of Sarnav Mukharji from BNK
securities. Please go ahead.
>> Hi sir, thank you for the opportunity.
Uh a couple of questions from my side.
first on the uh commission uh our
commission number that has increased uh
sequentially quite substantially because
I just wanted to understand that um
whether this is uh primarily due to our
retail products increasing in the mix or
uh whether you are seeing even in
commercial lines uh where you source
through maybe uh you know agents or
brokers that there has been an increase
in commission. So some color on what you
are seeing on the ground and just
because you know it's also fairly
topical that we are hearing about some
regulatory scrutiny on this side. So how
do you see the regulatory landscape
playing out? So that is the first one
and uh secondly on the group employer
employee I mean u so as you said uh that
uh the loss ratio numbers uh look fairly
encouraging. So just wanted to
understand that this loss ratio outcome
is this uh more a pricingled outcome or
is this that the claims environment has
become benign which is why we are seeing
this and our growth is this like uh also
a function of the base effect because
last year I think we were uh uh not
growing this business. So uh is that
playing out or have you become fairly
more constructive on this business than
you were earlier? Yeah, these will be my
two questions.
>> Okay, too many things into two
questions. So, yeah.
If you two questions are brilliant, we
will obviously try and address all of
them. Uh so, on the first one, Swarnab,
I think uh again this is something that
we always call out um uh and this is
what even Sanjiv just at the end
responded to one of the one of the uh
questions. See our our business has to
be fundamentally looked at in the
context of a loss experience and cost of
acquisition. So therefore to that action
there are always those nuances that play
out in terms of what mix of business
that you write. Uh relatively I I think
the earlier question that was asked in
terms of the mix between new and renewal
in terms of motor and my when I kind of
gave out the data points clearly you
would have seen that the proportion of
uh new was much higher particularly when
you looked at the quarter three numbers
this will be what we had seen for the
whole of 9 months. and new inherently
kind of comes with uh a high cost of
acquisition. Uh and hence to that extent
obviously and more importantly if you'd
have seen generally quarter 3 is is
typically a period of seasons. So and
more so in retail. So hence any quarter
three you go back you'll always find the
cost of acquisition to be relatively
higher than let's say what you would
have seen for other quarters. So there's
obviously an element of seasonality that
plays out when you look at the
commission uh numbers on an isolated
basis. But what we would keep saying is
to keep looking at it more on ideally
the overall combined ratio which for us
actually has dropped when you look at
the H1 numbers relative to the industry
adverse uh that has happened but and and
the second number that we keep talking
about is more on the overall expenses of
management. uh so even after considering
the impact of the uh wage code that I
spoke about of roughly about 55 crores
uh as at 9 months I think we are kind of
pretty much there uh in so far as the
limits that are laid down by the
regulatory guidelines. So hence to that
extent that's the way we would kind of
look at I think we are very very
conscious of what we kind of source and
very very conscious of what loss
experience and the cost of acquisition
that comes as a part of it. uh to the
second point on the regulatory uh uh uh
uh evolution on this. I think honestly
we we all have to kind of wait and see
how it plays out. I think the good news
is I think from a regulatory standpoint
the regulator has been kind of
instituting the right set of guidelines
for the industry. I think couple of
years back when they kind of introduced
this overall threshold on expense of
management that was a step in the that
was a step in the very right direction
of making sure that all companies all
costs put together are well within that
threshold of 30%. And if you look at
basis public disclosures uh roughly
there are still maybe almost 21 out of
34 players are maybe possibly met the
norms there are still a lot list of
companies which are still in exance on
the expense of management. So honestly I
think what we would want to see from a
market standpoint is to make sure that
every player in the market stays within
the limit on expensive management and
then honestly we will wait for any
subsequent changes that comes from a uh
uh regulatory changes but we will be
equally kind of committed to whatever
the guidelines that the regulator lays
down. Um so that's in response to the
first point on both commission increase
and what could happen in terms of
regulatory change. to your second point
on the GHI um yes it's a combination of
both I think again this is something
that we have articulated not only in the
context of GHI in general I think what
we have stayed focused on every line you
should see how we can remain profitable
and the very fact that the loss numbers
that I gave out is a testimony to the
fact that we have been very very careful
and selective in terms of what risk do
we want to underwrite uh equally it's
obviously a combination of uh both the
points that you made it's a combination
of let's say a better price in terms of
what we are comfortable underwriting and
two we have our own in-house claims
management team. I think they do a
brilliant job in terms of making sure
that once the once a group health
account is underwritten how is it that
we can play a very very important role
in managing the overall loss experience
and at the same time giving delight in
so far as customer experience is
concerned which is again reflective of
the NPS scores that we have kind of
called out uh whether it is motor or
whether it is health uh so that's so
that's how the growth has been reflected
and again we will continue to see that
play out even as we head into quarter
four even for the matter of fact the
next financial year.
>> Right sir and and so just on the first
question I wanted to also uh uh check on
the commercial line side. So is there
any kind of like for where you have a
intermediary source the deal has been a
commission inflation anything you can
>> honestly commercial lines in general I
think uh has been uh if you remember I
think what we have two is commercial
lines we have generally have we have our
own relationship team which acts as a
direct interface in so far as working
with corporates are concerned and hence
to that extent uh obviously relatively
that cost of sourcing tends to be very
very low but at the same time what we
also write as a part of of the
commercial lines is some ofme risks uh
which is which tends to be relatively
widely distributed and there there will
be an element of cost of distribution
but overall the point that I made when
you look at the loss experience plus the
cost of acquisition put together on the
commercial lines book that's a very very
profitable book for us and that's a way
how we look at it again rather than
looking at one element of uh the
business that we source
>> right sir got it that's very helpful
thank you so much sir
>> thank Hello.
>> Thanks for
>> Thank you.
We will take the last question from the
line of Nishin Chawat from Kota. Please
go ahead.
>> Yeah. Uh thanks for uh taking my
question. uh you know uh you have a very
impressive growth in retail health and
uh you know we can see an improvement in
uh you know retail uh loss ratios as
well but uh you know as as we understand
uh you know typically the lock ratios in
retail products are significantly lower
in the first uh you know 2 3 years and
then they kind of move up from there on.
So I would have kind of said that you
know this this this delta is because of
the portfolio mix. Is it something that
the new policies that are originated are
ported or they are they are originated
under under uh you know uh different
covenants or uh you know is is is the uh
you know is as a cohort level
profitability stable or improving or
deteriorating if you would give some
color on that.
So Nish again I think I'll I'll kind of
maintain the same response that I gave
in to the earlier question which is I
think the loss ratio range on retail
health as a company that we are
comfortable running at is between 65 to
70%. So that's a number that we will
keep looking for in terms of how we are
able to stay within that uh to a large
part of in terms of sourcing. I think
honestly what we want to do is in line
with let's say some of the uh some of
the discussions that even the government
has been doing to kind of increase uh
healthare or increase healthcare
penetration uh consequent to some of the
reforms that they have done is to kind
of improve penetration at large. So
hence I think where we are kind of
largely expanding our distribution reach
which is what we put out also as a part
of the opening transcript to say that
even on health we are do we do we are
seeing let's say an increase in tire two
tire three cities kind of contributing
and these are as we said new to
insurance uh so hence to that extent I
think so far as we are concerned uh we
would want to kind of uh continue to
expand by acquiring a lot many more new
to insurance uh customers and two and
more importantly the earlier point that
I said in terms of our ability to
continue to retain our own customers is
something that we are very much focused
on. So it will be a combination of those
two is what will continue to drive
growth in the retail book.
>> And uh just to add to what gopal is
saying see uh uh we've also transformed
our own journey right and we are a
multi-line multi-product company uh for
us whether the c customer comes from the
root of motor or from health uh we are
seeing it from a comprehensive one-stop
solution. we were uh underalled in our
offering for a number of years as far as
retail health is concerned and we know
that going in as we move along uh while
we all know that the loss ratios move
upward as we age and that's that's that
the truth which I don't see would change
but at the same time you also know if we
are comprehensively dealing with this
customer the motor loss is also goes
down I mean just to share with you so
it's a very clear mix and we are very
well placed as a multi-product
multi-line line company. So what we
seeing is getting a good customer on
board and then then working with them on
a lifetime profitability. So the maths
is what plays out with is what you see
because at times you will see only
health at times you will see only motor
but what we look at it is in a far more
comprehensive offering and with a 2.9%
market share which was just probably 18
months back for us to be a four four and
a half uh where we stand as we exist
quarter three it is just helping us to
build a very well-rounded practice. I'm
not saying it was not wellrounded but
health in particular was always in a
space which was driven by GHI and under
this part we see this as a toggling part
and we see it is a very significant play
in our scheme of thing that's why we've
got invested and we we stay positive and
business it's always possible that one
or two lines will have a problem and
COVID happened health was all over the
place but motor kind of saved the day
for us so that's the way the portfolio
gets balanced and that's Today we end up
talking about what is it that we can
generate as an ROE.
>> Yeah,
>> got it. That's that's very
comprehensive. Just uh squeezing the
last one. Uh I'm not sure if you
mentioned this but uh uh you know in
case of health uh you know there is uh
you know the the input tax credit loss
because of GST exemption. Uh so how are
you dealing with that? Are you sharing
it with the distributors or are you
absorbing it? Is that one of the drivers
for high expense ratios? So so so
clearly yes we will have to realign our
cost structure and this is what we have
done. The benefit in totality of GST
rationalization has got passed on to the
customers. Uh and uh we had the benefit
of as the volume grows uh for us it you
know in every line of business motor or
health economies of scale will kick in.
We have a large uh health practice as a
company which is in combined from the
employer employee as well as retail
health. So, so definitely we'll do what
is it required to rationalize it and
serve the customer appropriately. Yes.
>> Are you sharing it with the distributor
or
>> Yeah, of course. We have the industry
has shared. It's not only about us. We
all of us on the general insurance and
the retail health have uh and then the
increased volume is not impacting the
income of the distributor per se. So
there is already a counterplay which is
visible uh which can be seen in terms of
the growth. So it's not that it's one
channel which is getting impacted uh
comprehensively we are we are all able
to do better business. So yes, it's got
passed on. We have also a cost structure
because uh both part is required and
today's technology and the so much which
is going on which we have not spoken but
we can talk about it when we sit
onetoone is helping us also to reduce uh
cost per transaction. uh I don't know
when you see the script which I spoke
about as to how uh we've been able to
use uh you know bots uh uh to get our
digital part of serving DIY serving
significantly up with the uh you know
operator handling it which is driven by
a lot more inconsistency and uh you know
uh time consumption which can happen. So
there is so much that is happening. So
the cost part will go down. So we will
be able to manage it on this front very
easily.
>> Perfect. That's that's that's very very
reassuring. Uh thank you very much and
all the best.
>> Thank you. Thank you and all the best.
Thank you. Okay. Great. Uh thank you so
much for joining in and uh yeah.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. Thank you and have a great
2026. Thank you so much.
>> Thank you. Thank you on behalf of ICIC
Lombard General Insurance Company
Limited. That concludes this conference.
Thank you all for joining us and you may
now disconnect your lines.
>> Thank you so much. Thank
you.